rekhta.org 2019-06-10

# 

**Introduction **

Rekhta Foundation is a public charitable trust established with the objective of promotion, development and advancement of Urdu and Hindustani languages through various media. Our contact details are available at the **[Contact Us](https://www.rekhta.org/contact-us)** page. We are committed to protecting your privacy and the privacy of any personally identifiable information that we collect.

 **Scope **

Third Party Websites   
The service may contain links to third party websites that are not controlled by [Rekhta](https://www.rekhta.org/). This Privacy Policy only applies to the information we collect when you use the services of [ Rekhta](https://www.rekhta.org/) and does not apply to any third party website. We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the Service, including Partner Sites, or the information or content contained thereon. 

Age Limit

The service is intended for anyone above 18 years of age or any minor who has the consent of parent or guardian. We do not knowingly collect any personal information of anyone other than the aforementioned persons. 

**Collection of Information **

When you visit our website we collect information relating to you and your use of our services from a variety of sources. The sources and the information they collect are listed below: 

Information we collect directly from you

Registration Information:  When you register for an account with[ rekhta.org ](https://www.rekhta.org/)we collect your name, email address, place of residence, contact details (including phone No.), date of birth, occupation and password. If you log in with or connect to your account through a third party site (Facebook, Google, etc.), the third party may pass on information to us, such as user ID, the name associated with the ID, email address and location in addition to other information permitted under the privacy policy for that website. The third party’s use of such information will be governed by their privacy policy. 

Information collected during Event Registration: During Registration for Events on [rekhta.org](https://www.rekhta.org/), we may collect you name, email address, city, phone number and age. 

Information you directly share: Any information you directly share on the website such as information shared in comments, critiques shall be stored with us and we may display the same indefinitely subject to our editorial judgement and your rights as per this policy. 

Information we collect passively when you interact with us 

Usage data: whenever you interact with our website we collect usage information which includes the webpages you visit, your language preference, what particular elements you interact with and click on, when you perform such actions etc. 

Device data: We further collect information from the device by which you access our website and services. Such information may include your IP address, which browser you are using, UUID details (for phones), operating system details, device details and system information. 

We might use cookies to store preferences and to record session information

 **Use of This Information **

The information we collect is used to improve the content of our website and your experience, to promote in-house events and for donation campaigns. We do not rent, sell, or share your personal information with any unaffiliated third party or organization. The data may be shared with third party service providers such as newsletter sending agency, registrations-validation agency at our events etc.   
If you supply us with your telephone, postal and/or email address online you may receive periodic updates from us with information on new services or upcoming events.   
Any information we collect is also shared with the websites which are members of the Rekhta Group. A list of the websites which are members of the Rekhta Group is given below: 

We might have to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us. The lawful basis may be gauged from the following table which is representative in nature and not exhaustive:

Purpose or activity | Types of Personal data| Lawful Basis  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new visitor| 

  * a)Identity
  * b)Contract
  * c)Technical

| Performance of a contract with you  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

  * a) Notifying you about the changes to our terms or privacy policy 
  * b) Asking you to leave a review

| 

  * a)Identity
  * b)Contract
  * c)Profile

| 

  * a) Performance of a contract with you
  * b) Necessary to comply with legal obligation
  * c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our service).

To administer and protect our business and this service (Including troubleshooting, data analytics, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of the data)| 

  * a)Identity
  * b)Contract
  * c)Technical

| 

  * d) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise).
  * e) Necessary to comply with legal obligation

To deliver relevant content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you| 

  * a)Identity
  * b)Contract
  * c)Technical
  * d)Profile   

  * e)Usage

| 

  * a) Consent. When you have provided explicit consent to our use of your personal data to provide you with relevant advertising and personalized content. 
  * b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how our customers use our services).

To use data analytics to improve our service| 

  * a)Identity
  * b)Usage

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy).  
To send you newsletter and promotional emails that may interest you| 

  * a)Identity
  * b)Contract
  * c)Technical
  * d)Usage
  * e)Profile

| 

  * f) Consent. When you have provided explicit consent to receive such emails. 
  * g) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our Service and grow our business).

 **Correcting This Information **

Upon a reasonable and genuine request, we can provide you access to the personally identifiable information that we maintain about you. Upon request we also offer you the ability to have inaccuracies corrected in the information. You can access this information and/or have inaccuracies corrected in the information by emailing us at the below address, calling us at the phone number, or writing to us at our address. 

**Other rights with respect to your data **

A.  Opting Out of Emails and Newsletters: If you do not want to receive e-mails or newsletters from us in the future, you can do so by not tick marking the check box when such details are being taken or by clicking unsubscribing link shared in the email. 

B. Denying Cookies:  If you do not want to accept our cookies, you can adjust your browser settings to decline cookies. You should note, however, that certain areas of the Site may not operate properly if you decide not to accept cookies. 

C. Request restriction on processing: This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

D.  Requesting erasure of data:  This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing, where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

E.  Withdrawing Consent: This may be exercised where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

 **Retention of Data **

A. We will only retain your Personal Data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. 

B.To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. 

**Updates to This Policy **

If our privacy practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our website. 

**Grievance Mechanism **

If you feel that this site is not following its stated privacy policy, or if you have any questions or concerns regarding the same, please contact our Grievance Officer, at the following address–

Grievance Officer   
Rekhta Foundation   
ADDRESS: B-37, Sector-1, Noida- 201301   
PHONE: 0120-2443716   
Email: [contact@rekhta.org](mailto:contact@rekhta.org)
